Register of the World War I subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed matter, relief organizations, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  Leaflets, cards, flyers, booklets, form letters, and other printed matter published by a wide variety of French relief organizations. In French.
- Telegraphie, 1915 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  Two telegrams, both stamped Wloclawek (a town in northern Poland). One is dated 25 February 1915, the other 21 April 1915. In German.
- Feld-Presse I-V, Kriegsnachrichtendienst, Subject File, 1914-1918 (Boxes 6-9)
  These materials were organized and numbered by the original collector, and that order was maintained when placing them into folders. Folder titles were created based upon the titles of the publications within them.
  - Leaflets from Łukowski, 1917 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    Two leaflets related to Łukowski, Poland. One, titled "Protokół" and dated June 28, 1917, consists of meeting minutes of the regional council of the district (in Polish). The other, titled "Budżet powiatowy" and dated 1917, consists of the county budget for 1917 (in German and Polish).
  - "Pinsker Zeitung,", 1915 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - "Deutsche Nachrichten vom Kriege,", 1914 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    Three issues, dated 27 October 1914, 20 November 1914, and 26 November 1914.
  - "Tagesbericht der Armee-Zeitung Jildirim,", 1918 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - "Armeegruppe Carlowitz,", 1916 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," A.O.K. 3 and 4, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    Leaflets from A.O.K. 4 are dated December 27 and 28, 1914. Leaflets from A.O.K. 3 are dated 1915-1917, though all months in those years are not represented.
  - "Blätter für Auskunftswesen;" "Nachrichtenblatt," Herausgegeben vom A.D.K. 4, Abteilung, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    "Blätter für Auskunftswesen:" Number 10 (31 December 1917), Number 11 (15 January 1918), Number 15 (14 March 1918), Number 19 (31 May 1918), and Number 20 (19 June 1918). "Nachrichtenblatt:" Number 8 (15 January 1918).
  - "Funk-Spruch von Norddeich (Zeitungsdienst),", 1914 October 19-24 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - "Funkspruch," Aufgenommen von der Funkenstation des A.O.K. der 7. Armee, 1917 June 3 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - "M.W. Funken-Station I," A.O.K. 10., 1916 January 25 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - "Schwere Funkenstation 12," A.O.K. 10, 1915 November 19 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Akonach 21 Flugblätter, 1918 February 6-12 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - "Deutscher Heeresbericht. Comunicat Oficial German,", 1917 (Box-folder 6: 17)
    In German and Romanian.
  - "Argonnen-Post. Neueste Nachrichten,", 1916-1917 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - "Nachrichtendienst," 18. Inf. Div., 1915-1916 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - "Neueste Nachrichten," Herausgegeben von der 34. Inf.-Div., 1916 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - "Neueste Nachrichten," Herausgegeben von der 34. Inf.-Div., 1917 (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
  - "Graben Post,", 1918 July 16 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Fensprech-Abtlg. der 79. R.-D.,", 1916 August 7 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Funksprüche, Generalkommando XI. A.-K., 1915 - 1916 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - "Funkenspruch,", 1915 September 27 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    In German, Polish, Lithuanian and Yiddish.
  - "Res. Fernsprech-Abteilung 40," General-Kommando XXXX, Reserve-Korps, 1916 July 7 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - "Schwere Funken-Station 33," General-Kommando XXXX, Reserve-Korps, 1916 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - "General-Gouvernement Brüssel, Funkspruch-Nachrichten,", 1915-1916 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - "Funker-Zeitung," Hauptquartier Ost, 1916 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - "Nachrichtenblatt der Heeresgruppe Deutscher Kronprinz,", 1918 April (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - "Grosses Hauptquartier, Westlicher und Östlicher Kriegsschauplatz,", 1917 July 8 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - "Heeresbericht," Druckerei Gardekorps, 1917 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - "Susita-Zeitung;" "Neueste Nachrichten für das Gouvernement Sewastopol und Umgegend;" "Neueste Kriegs-Nachrichten," Presse-Abteilung, Heeresgruppe Kiew, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    "Susita-Zeitung:" 2 December 1917 - 7 January 1918. "Neueste Nachrichten…:" 12-20 June 1918. "Neueste Kriegs-Nachrichten…:" 15 October 1918.
  - "Deutscher Heeresbericht," Grosses Hauptquartier, Druckerei Garde-Reserve-Korps, 1917 January 4-23 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - "Feld-Zeitung der 217. Infanterie-Division;" "Tages-Nachrichten,", 1917 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    "Feld-Zeitung…:" 7, 12 June, 13 July, 26 September, 7 November 1917. "Tages-Nachrichten:" 26-27 November 1917.
  - "Korrespondenz der Zeitung der 10. Armee,", 1916 (Box-folder 7: 18)
    Month names are in "Poetic German."
  - "IIIb Feldpressestelle,", 1918 May 15 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - "Korrespondenz B.,", 1916-1917 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - "Nachrichten-Dienst der Kaiserlichen Kommandantur Kowno,", 1915 September 20-28 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - "Funker-Zeitung der Leichten Funken-Station 1,", 1916 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - "Legerbericht,", 1917 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    In Dutch.
  - "Letzte Kriegsnachrichten," Grosses Hauptquartier/"Dernières Nouvelles de la Guerre," Grand Quartier Général, 1915 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - "Neueste Kriegsnachrichten," Grosses Hauptquartier, 1916 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - "Mitteilungen aus dem besetzten Gebiet des Westens,", 1917-1918 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - "Nachrichtenblatt der 17. Armee,", 1918 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - "Nachrichtenblatt für die Kameraden im Kampf zwischen Somme u. Oise aus der 'Stafette in Champagne und Argonnen,'", 1918 May 26 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - "Nachrichten," gez. v. Bockelberg, Generalleutnant und Etappen-Inspekteur/"Nouvelles," signé v. Bockelberg, Lieutenant-Général, Commandant des Étapes, 1915 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - "Nachrichtendienst vom 4.11.1918 nachts,", 1918 November 4 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - "Neuste [sic] Meldungen," Amtlich: Grosses Hauptquartier, Westlicher Kriegsschauplatz, 1918 June (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - "Neueste Kriegs-Nachrichten," Staden, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - "Neueste Kriegsnachrichten, Deutscher Heeresbericht,", 1918 May 4 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - "Neueste Kriegsnachrichten," Grosses Hauptquartier, Westlicher Kriegsschauplatz/"Dernières Nouvelles de la Guerre," Grand Quartier Général, Champs de bataille occidentaux, 1915 January 28 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - "Letzte Kriegsnachrichten,", 1916 October 6-23 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - "Der Funke, Nachrichtendienst des Regts. Bliesener,", 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - "Verstärktes III. Res.-Korps,", 1916-1917 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," IX. Reserve-Korps, 1916 September 4 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - "Truppen Nachrichtenblatt der Gruppe Wijtschate,", 1918 July (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - "Von den Kriegsschauplätzen,", 1916 February 6 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - "Kriegs-Nachrichten Warna,", 1917 March 7 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - "Heeresbericht/Zeitungsdienst,", 1916 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Herausgegeben von der Gruppe Arras, 1917 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Herausgegeben von der Gruppe Arras, 1918 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - "Zeitungsdienst der Division," Deutscher Heeresbericht, 1917 February 23 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Norddeich, Köln und Paris, 1915 October 27-29 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    In German and French.
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Heeresgruppe Kronprinz Rupprecht, 1918 June (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Der Erste Generalquartiermeister Ludendorff, 1918 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - "Zeitungs-Dienst der Gruppe Flandern,", 1918 April 22 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Gedruckt in der Champagne-Kriegszeitung, 1915 November 3-8 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - "Zeitung der 10. Armee, Funkerdienst,", 1917 May (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - "Zeitungsdienst, Wörtlicher Abdruck des dem General-Kommando durch den Fernsprecher übermittelten Zeitungsdienstes,", 1915-1916 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Korpsdruckerei des IX. Res.-Korps, 1916 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    Some have contemporaneous handwriting on the back.
  - "Zeitungs-Dienst," Deutscher Heeresbericht, 1918 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - "Zeitungsdienst," Funkspruch aus Königswusterhausen und Wien, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - "Zeitungsdienst für Abschnitt St. Marie-a-Py--Somme-Py;" "Deutscher Zeitungsverlag," Roeselare, Markt, 8; Spruch aus Norddeich; Spruch aus Berlin; "Zeitungsdienst," Gedruckt in der Felddruckerei des Marinekorps, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 9: 13)
- Heeres Tagesbefehle, Kommandantur und Lagerbefehle, Subject File, 1914-1918, undated (Box-folder 9: 14-20)
  Germany military documents; title given by original collector. In German and French.
  - Undated, circa 1914-1918 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - 1914 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - 1915 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - 1916 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - 1917 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - 1918 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - "Avis et Ordres de la Commandanture,", circa 1916-1917 (Box-folder 9: 20)
- Army Theatrical Performances, Subject File, 1914-1918 (Box 10)
  These materials were organized and titled by the original collector, and the organization and titles were maintained when placing the materials into folders.
  - Programme I., 1915-1918 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    Concert and theater programs, also includes Sportfest and Lichtspiele programs. Performances in Aubigny, Breisach, Brügge, Brussels, Bucharest, Buzancy, Cambrai, Charleroi, Corbon, Dusseldorf, Elbing, Fouquières, Ghent, Ghistel, Givet, Hirson, Jelowka, Juniville, Keyem, Königsberg, Krusevica, Lecluse, Levico, Lille, Lislet, Longwy, Lötzen, Lüttich, Marville, Maubeuge, Mouzon, Namur, Nanteuil, Ostend, Poniewicz, Posen, Roeselare, St. Amand.
  - Programme II., 1914-1918 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    Concert and theater programs. Performances in St. Quentin, St. Ludwig, Sinceny, Sigmundsherberg, Tarnopol, Ulm, Untertürkheim, Walsrode, Warsaw, Wilma, Wolcy-Las Wolhynien. Truppe performances - Abt. 2; Polish material - Abt. 3. Nos. 1-11; Roumania - Abt. 3. Nos. 12-21; Smyrna and Turkey - Abt. 3. Nos. 22-45; three German posters at end of file.
  - Programme III., 1914-1916 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    Concert and theater programs. Prisoners of War. Performances in Amberg, Cassel, Doberitz, Dülmen, Erfurt, Hameln, Hahnöfersand, Lechfeld, Lichtenhorst, Nuremberg, Senne, Weinberge, Zossen. Also some POW camps in UK.
- Books and Pamphlets, 1897, 1903, 1912-1920, undated (Boxes 11-12)
  - Leitfaden für den Kavalleristen, 1916 (Box 11)
  - Kriegsbilder aus der Bibel, undated
  - Des Grossen Krieges Not, 1915
  - Sonne und Schild, 1918
  - Zu Wehr und Ehr', 1916
  - Ratschläge und Mitteilungen, circa 1912
  - Wir sind Wir, undated
  - Wann ist Frieden?, undated
  - Reformation und Weltkrieg, 1917
  - Kalander für Heimat und Heer, 1919
  - Neufelds Sprachführer Russisch, undated
  - Wie ein stolzer Adler, undated
  - Unser oberster Kriegsher im Felde, circa 1915
  - Die Tragik in des Kaisers Leben, circa 1916
  - Beese Zeiden, undated
  - Feldgraves Bildungswesen in Rumänien, 1920
  - Warschau, 1919
  - Sachsens Militär Vereins-Kalender auf das jar, 1916
  - "Ein Pfingstgruss aus der Heimat,", undated
  - "Fromm und Deutsch. Ein Geleitwort zur Konfirmation im Jahre des grossen Krieges,", 1914
  - "Des Kaisers Worte an seine Söhne,", 1903
  - "Die heulende Wölfin,", 1917
  - "Heer und Heimat in vier Kriegsjahren,", circa 1918
  - "Deutsche Kriegsanleihe,", 1917
  - "Das Kriegs Sparwesen,", 1918
  - "Leitfaden für die Werbearbeit zur 8. Kriegsanleihe,", undated
  - "Der Weltkrieg, der Geheimen Offenbarung und was auf ihn folgt,", 1920
  - "Einfache Worte an den einfachen Mann,", undated
  - "Die Verwaltung von Wertpapieren,", undated
  - "Nachtrag zum Leitfaden für die Werbearbeit zugunsten der Kriegsanleihe,", undated
  - "Deutsch französischer Soldaten Sprachführer,", undated
  - "Ein lustig Büchel Soldatendeutsch,", undated
  - "Kriegsrätsel,", 1917
  - "Sammelnde Trommel. Lieder in die Not der Zeit,", 1917
  - "Trommelfeuer,", 1916 (Box 12)
  - "Treue Wacht," No. 3284, undated
  - "Aus grosser Zeit,", 1917
  - "Neue Kriegsgedichte 1914/15,", 1916
  - "Zur VII. Kriegsanleihe. Leitfaden und Nachschlageblätter zur Werbearbeit,", undated
  - "Grosse mehrfarbige Kriegsbilder zu 2 Mark,", undated
  - "Feldgesangbuch für die evangelische Mannschaften des Heeres,", 1897
  - "Das grosse Mitleid von einem Kriegsfreiwilligen,", 1915
  - "Bethesda-Kalendar 1916,"
  - "Siehe, ich bin bei Euch! Ein Weihnachtsgruss an die deutsche Armee,", 1915
  - "Gott im Leide,", 1915
  - "Gute Wehr und Waffen für unsere Soldaten,", 1914
  - "Singbüchlein für Soldaten. Heer und Flotte,", 1914
  - "Zukunftshoffen. Kriegsgedichte eines Feldgrauen,", 1917
  - "Leitfaden zur 9. Kriegsanleihe,", 1918 August
  - "Sturmzeit,", 1919
  - "Deutsche Heldenstücklein im Weltkriege 1914-1915,", circa 1915
  - "Deutsches Soldaten-Liederbuch,", undated
  - "Kriegs-, Soldaten- und Vaterländische Lieder,", 1915
  - "Deutscher Soldatenfreund Kalender 1915,"
  - "Wunden. Das Lachen,", 1918
  - "Gott ist unsere Zuversicht,", 1915
  - "O Deutschland hoch in Ehren!,", 1914
  - "Ein seste Burg ist unser Gott,", 1914
  - "Gott mit uns!,", 1914
  - "Ein guter Kamerad,", 1916
  - "Deutscher Soldatenfreund Kalander 1917,"
  - "Eineges über den englischen Volkscharakter,", undated
  - "An die deutsche Jugend im Weltkriegersjahr 1914,"
  - "Ein Jahrtausend bulgarische Geschichte,", 1917
  - "Deutsches Gebet. Kanzelrede gehalten am 6 Oktober 1918 in der evangelische reformierten Kirche zu Leipzig,"
  - "Die gegenwärtige Völkerkrise im Lichte der Bibel,", 1920
  - "Scholz' künstlerische Volks-Bilderbücher. Unsere Feldgrauen,", undated
  - "Gottesfriede,", 1918
  - "Vaterländische Gesänge und Soldatenlieder,", 1914
  - "Der arme Konrad. Kalander für das arbeitende Volk,", 1919
  - "Vaterländischer Volkskalender,", 1920
  - "Leitfaden zur 9. Kriegsanleihe,", 1918
  - "Praktische Ratschläge für die Werbearbeit zur Kriegsanleihe im Heere,", 1918
  - "Gedenkschrift. Reiseprüfungen am k. k. Staatsrealgymnasium in Graz im grossen Kriegsjahre 1914-1915,"
  - "Das Weissbuch des deutschen Inserenten,", undated
  - "Das deutsche Lied 1914," with enclosures
  - Von der Front, circa 1915
  - Paris. Eine Erinnerung und eine Hoffnung, 1914
- Weltkrieg, Subject File, 1914-1921 (Boxes 13, 17)
  These materials were organized, numbered, and titled by the original collector, and the order and titles were maintained when placing the materials into folders. Materials separated by size.
  - Bargeldloser Zahlungsverkehr, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Verschiedene Kriegswohltätigkeitsspenden, 1914-1920 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Kriegsausstellungen in Deutschland und Österreich-Ungarn; Kriegsbilder; Kriegskunst Blätter und Gedenkblätter in Kunst, circa 1916-1918 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Kriegsgefangenenwesen und Freigabe derselben: Freigabe deutscher Kriegsgefangenen, circa 1916-1920 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    Some materials are in French, Russian, and Dutch.
  - Programme für Veranstaltungen; Mauerenanschlagen aus den Besetzten Gebiete; Almanache aus der Kriegszeit, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    Some materials are also in Lithuanian and Polish.
  - Plakate zur Ermahnung und Verwarnung der Soldaten; Militärische Jugenderziehung im Weltkrieg, 1914-1918, undated (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Kriegsreden und Kriegserlasse, 1917-1918, undated (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Lebensmittelversorgung [1 of 3], 1915-1921 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Obstkern, Bucheckern, Eicheln, Laub, et. Sammlungen, 1917-1918, undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Amtliche Goldsammlung, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Metall Ablieferung und Ablieferung von Gegenstanded aus Aluminum, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Ludendorffe Spende für Kriegsbeschädigte, 1918, undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Rotes Kreuz, circa 1914 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Formulare über Beschlangnahmungen während des Weltkrieges, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Reklame im Krieg, undated (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Mobilmachung und Musterungen, 1915, 1918, undated (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Heimkehr der Truppen in die Garnison nach Kriegsende, circa 1918 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Wissenschaft und Weltkrieg, circa 1915-1918 (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Friedensgesellschaften, circa 1914-1920 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Fliegerabwurfschriften, circa 1916-1918 (Box-folder 17: 12)
    Some materials are in Romanian and French.
  - Elsass Lothringische Frage, 1919 April 3 (Box-folder 17: 13)
    3 April 1919 issue of Der Bund. Some miscellaneous materials were also found inside the newspaper (a bookmark, a postcard, and a slip of paper) which do not appear to be about Elsass Lothringische.
  - Kriegsamt (Vaterländische Hilfsdienst), circa 1917-1918 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    An armband that originally was with these materials was moved to the memorabilia box, Box 44.
  - Selbstständigkeitserklärung und deutsche Verwaltung Polens, circa 1916 (Box-folder 17: 15)
    In Polish and Yiddish.
  - Die Kirche und Religion im Weltkrieg, circa 1914-1918 (Box-folder 17: 16)
  - Lebensmittelversorgung [2-3 of 3], 1914-1921 (Box-folder 17: 17-18)
    Food stamps/ration cards. Some materials are in Slovak.
  - Vaterländische Unterricht, circa 1917-1918 (Box-folder 17: 19)
- Revolution, Subject File, 1914, 1917-1920 (Boxes 13-18)
  - Bekämpfung des Bolschewismus, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Volksabstimmungen. Abtrennung deutscher Gebietsteile, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Streikbekämpfung, Hebung der Arbeits Leistung, 1914, 1919-1920, undated (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Aufrufe der deutschen Regierung an das Deutsche Volk, undated (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Jugendbewegung im Revolution, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Propagierung des Rätesystems, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Einigung des Proletariats, circa 1919 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Maifeiern, 1914, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Reichsbetriebsräte Gesetz und die anschliessende Vorgänge, circa 1920 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Branschbewegung in der Revolution; Werbung von Freiwilligen für Reichswehr und techniche Nothilfe, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Befehlshaber militärischer Formationen; Revolutionäre Bewegung in Berlin; Revolutionäre Bewegung in München, circa 1918-1919 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Revolutionäre Bewegung in Leipzig; Revolutionäre Bewegung in Bremen; Revolutionäre Bewegung in Ruhrenkohlengebiete; Revolutionbewegung in Deutschösterreich, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Hilfsaktion für das notleidende Deutschösterreich; Reklame für Zeitungen in der Revolution; Wiederbeschaffung gestohlenen Heeresguter, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Zwangswirtschaft, freier Handel, Schieber und Wucherthum; Auslieferungsfrage deutscher Heerfuhrer usw.; Erscheinungen der Liga zum Schutze der Deutschen Kultur, circa 1917-1920 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Die Frau und die Wahlen in der Revolution; Die Wahlen zur verfassunggegebenen deutschen Nationalversammlung, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Wahlen zum ersten deutschen Revolutions-Reichstag, circa 1920 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Wahlen zu den Stadtparlamenten; Dokumente auf alle Wahlen bezuglich; Sowjet Republik München vom Februar bis Ende April 1919, circa 1919 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Gegenrevolution Kapp Lüttwitz im März 1920 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Kommunistische Arbeiterpartei Deutschlands; Vereinigte Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands, circa 1919-1921 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Unabhängige Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Deutsch-Sozialistische Partei; Bayerische Volkspartei und Zentrumspartei, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Bürgerausschuss, Bürgervereinigungen, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Verschiedene andere kleine Parteien und Vereinigungen, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    There is one item that is in Esperanto.
  - Deutsche Demokratische Partei, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Deutsche Volkspartei, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Friedensschluss von Versailles, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 17: 20)
  - Auswanderungsfrage, Siedlungsfrage, 1920, undated (Box-folder 17: 21)
  - Arbeitslosenwesen, 1919, undated (Box-folder 17: 22)
  - Plakatsäulenkampf der Unabhängigen Leipziger Volkszeitung mit dem Leipziger Bürgerausschuss, circa 1919 (Box-folder 17: 23)
  - Juden in Revolution, circa 1918-1920 (Box-folder 17: 24)
  - Antisemitische Bewegung, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 17: 25)
  - Schulreform, Trennung Kirche und Schule Elternbeiräte, circa 1919-1920 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Literatur über und gegen Erzberger, 1919, undated (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Gedenkfeier an den Ausbruch der deutschen Revolution, 1919 November 9 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Sonstige veranstaltungen in der Revolution, 1920 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Kunst und Revolution, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Revolutionäre Bewegung unter den Eisenbahnern, circa 1919 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- Bibliography, "Bibliographie des Ouvrages Publiés en Norvège,", undated (Box-folder 18: 7)
  "Tracts, brochures, rapports publies en Norvege pendant et depuis la guerre."
- Book, Die Kriegssammlung Theodor Bergmann in Fürth (Bayern), 1920 (Box-folder 18: 8)
- Book, Der Luft-Krieg: Luftkrieg/Luftschiffahrt/Flugwesen, 1915 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  Mit einer Einführung von Major von Parseval, herausgegeben von Paul Béjeuhr. Mit rund 150 photogr. Aufnahmen und Text. Der Gelbe Verlag in Dachau bei München.
- Booklet, "La Acción Social Obrera en Alemania,", 1918 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  Por Robert Schmidt, Miembro del Parlamento Alemán, y J. Giesberts, Secretario del Partido Obrero. 4. edición.
- Booklet, "The Attack in Position Warfare,", 1918 October 11 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  Translation of a German document. From the "Manual of Position Warfare for All Arms, Part 14 (Provisional)." Issued by the Chief of the General Staff of the Field Army.
- Booklet, "Scraps of Paper: German Proclamations in Belgium and France,", 1916 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  With a foreword by Ian Malcolm, M.P. Includes one complete copy (without cover), and one copy of the proclamations without the cover or the foreword. The booklet consists of reproductions of posters and placards posted by the Germans in invaded towns in Belgium and France with translations and commentary.
- Correspondence and postcards, 1915, 1918-1919, undated (Box-folder 18: 13)
  "Kirchner's Korrespondenz für Kriegssammler" (1919), notes, and some blank postcards to be used by prisoners of war (in German, French, English and Russian).
- Flyer, "Anzeiger für das Havelland,", 1917 January 19 (Box-folder 18: 14)
- Flyer, "Bekanntmachung. Das Monopol des Kaufmanns Freitag ist aufgehoben…,", 1918 January (Box-folder 18: 15)
  In German, Polish, Russian and Yiddish.
- Flyer, "Bekanntmachung. … ist es im Gouvernementsbereich streng verboten, Kuchen irgend welcher Art zu backen,", 1916 February 24 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  In German, Lithuanian and Polish.
- Flyer, "Hüte dich vor Geschlechtskrankheiten!,", 1916 January (Box-folder 18: 17)
- Flyer, "Merkblatt für Männer zur Verhütung von Geschlechtskrankheiten,", 1916 January (Box-folder 18: 18)
- Graphs, variations in German morale, 1914-1918, undated (Box-folder 18: 19)
- Index, German ration cards, undated (Box-folder 18: 20)
  Multiple indices listing and describing different varieties of ration cards in use during World War I.
- Index, Kriegs-Urkunden-Sammlung (Urkunden zur Geschichtsschreibung), undated (Box-folder 18: 21)
  Forward and index to "Sammlung der offiziellen Bekanntmachungen und Verordnungen von hohem historischen Wert. Insgesammt 1210 einzelne Urkunden," August 1914 - November 1918.
- Index, Systematische Sammlung der Drucksachen, des Werbematerials und der Plakate zu den 9 deutschen Kriegsanleihen, undated (Box-folder 18: 22)
- Leaflets, Befehle, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 18: 23)
  Military orders from the German Army.
- Leaflet, "Die Kanzlerrede vom 27. Februar 1917,", 1917 February (Box-folder 18: 24)
- Newspapers and clippings, 1914, 1918 (Box-folder 18: 25)